Guide to the Maurice Durand Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Visual materials, Circa 1950-circa 1959; Series III
  - Hong Kong
    - Ice House Street, Kennedy Town, decorations for the Fête nationale de la République démocratique chinoise, 10 photographs, 1956 October 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Shankiwan, families, 33 photographs, 1956 October 31-November 12 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chinese theater actors, 9 photographs, 1956 October 31 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Victoria Harbor, waterfront, sampans and junks, 22 photographs, 1956 October 1-15 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Wanchai district facades, 4 photographs, 1956 October 15 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - West Point market, 16 photographs, 1956 October 15 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Yee Wo Street, Causeway Bay, street scenes and vistas of Mount Cameron, Hennessy Road, Queen's Road, 50 photographs, 1956 October 1-27 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Cheung Chan, street scenes, markets, temples, workers, port scenes, water taxis, boatwork on a junk, 40 photographs, 1956 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Kam Tin, village fortifications, gates, bridge, streets, stele, 27 photographs, 1956 December 17 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Kau Sai (Port Shelter), port scenes, streets, children, adults, drying fish, 36 photographs (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Kowloon, Shaw Building (Nathan Rd.), street scenes, open-air market, soy fermentation, shoe store, fruit drying, aerial views of harbor, 38 photographs, 1956 October 6-November 8 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Ping Chau, women and children working, boat repair, sampans and barques, port scenes, commercial street, 33 photographs, 1956 October 21 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Sai Kung (Inner Port Shelter), temple, street scenes, children, women, pigs, terraces, farm communities, tile roofs, funerary jars, port scenes, sampans and junks, marriage festivities, 94 photographs, 1956 October 17-November 8 (Box 16, Folder 18 - 20)
    - Sha Tin, marriage celebrations, villagers, pigs, families, Needle Hill district, typical dress, terraces, farming, homes, rice cultivation, 130 photographs, 1956 October 7-December 19 (Box 17, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Tai O, families, boat repair, 12 photographs, 1956 November 10 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Tai Po, market, rice store, iron utensils, harbor scenes, 22 photographs, 1956 October 3 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Tap Mun (Grass Island), houses, temple, aerial views of bay, funerary urns, restaurant, sacred tree, 8 photographs, 1956 November 12 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Chinese art
    - Chinese Jade par Nott (Stanley Charles), symbols, 8 photographs, 1955 April (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Popular Chinese imagery, male figures, 23 photographs, 1956 October (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Vietnam, Hanoi, Vietnamese art
    - Religious sculpture, popular imagery, 41 photographs, 1956 May-July (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Popular imagery, 32 photographs, 1952 September-1957 April (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Vietnam
    - Phu Gay Nam Dinh, religious festival, Phy Van temple, 6 photographs, 1957 April 6 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Vietnam and Laos, Musée Louis Finot, Vietnamese art, bronze drums, 37 photographs, 1956 May (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Den Hung, Phu Tho, ritual restival (Hung Vuong temple), 2 photographs, 1957 April 9 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - La Huynh, Quang Ngai, decorative bronze vase, bowls, and goblets, 4 photographs, 1957 February (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Quang Yen (Musée Louis Finot), commission and flag of a wizard (sorcier), 2 photographs, 1955 January (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Yen Lac, Vinh Yen, Vietnamese portrait paintings on paper, 10 photographs, 1955 January-1956 September (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Vietnam and China, Vietnamese art and religious architecture, handwritten caption information in French on the back of each, 30 photographs, Circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Photograph album, Tap Anh Ky Niem Ngay Mung Ho Chu Tich Va Chinh Phu Ve Thu Do, portraits of Vietnamese leaders and military parades with captions in Vietnamese, Circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Vietnamese iconograph of Trieu Au, photocopy, Circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Plan Vietnam ancien, hand-colored map on tracing paper scroll, Undated (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Map of Chùa Trần Quốc Trần Quốc Buddhist Temple, Undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Color slides of imagerie populaire, 16 slides, Undated (Box 19, Folder 41)
- Research notes, Circa 1930-circa 1966; Series IV
  This series comprises loose and bound research notes in French on a variety of topics relating to Chinese and Vietnamese literature, culture, and linguistics. It also includes a photocopy of Durand's thesis and related materials on Tay Son. Exact dates for materials in this series could not be determined.
  - Đại Nam Chính Biên and many other Vietnamese and Chinese sources of selected passage in Chinese and French, translations and annotations (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
  - Index des caracteres (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Tây Sơn typescript (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Tây Sơn Liệt Truyện [photocopy] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Tây Sơn Bang Giao Tâp [photocopy] (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Tây Sơn Thuật Lươc, French translation (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - List of name changes from pre- to post-Tây Sơn era (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Research paper in French, translations by Durand; History of Vietnam; Vietnamese Women Literature; Buddhism related topics;Tây Sơn binder (Box 22, Folder 7-10)
    - "Lê Nam Sử Diên Ca" poem, research paper in French (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographie (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Hương Tích; Quan Âm, research paper in French (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - An Nam phong thổ thoại, research paper in Vietnamese (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Quốc Phong Thi Hơp Thải, research paper in Vietnamese (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Le Poems Trung, research paper in French and Nom (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Liễu Hạnh, research paper in French (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Histoire du Vietnam, research paper in French (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Hồng Đức Quốc Âm Thi Tập, research paper in French (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Le Vietnam sous les Han, in French (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Notebook on Ca Dao; Hồ Xuân Hương, in French (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Durand's research papers and notes in French with no clear titles (Box 24, Folder 1-14)
    - Durand's four notebooks (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
    - Durand's notebook about Phan Tran, in Nom and Vietnamese (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Đặng Trần Côn, in French (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Kiều," in French (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Phan Tran, in Nom Vietnamese (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - "Kim Cỗ Ky quan Phong Dic̣h," in Vietnamese (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Durand's papers and notes in French with no clear titles (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
- Microfilm, Circa 1825-1955; Series V
  This series contains ninety-four reels of microfilm purchased by Durand in the early 1950s from the École française d'Extrême-Orient in Paris. They are primarily of early 20th-century published texts in Han and Nom with Vietnamese transliterations, or in Vietnamese only. Titles of the texts on each microfilm are transcribed from the initial frames of each microfilm; exact dates are supplied only when available on the microfilm. Exact dates for much of the material in this series could not be determined. Numbers included in the title of each microfilm reflect numbers that appear on the films or the original boxes. The numbers may be related to a variety of lists and inventories that accompanied the collection and can now be found in box 121.
  - Lê Triều Ngự Chế Âm Thi/Posies en Langue Nationale Composeis Fan le Seignuer (Reel 27)
  - Lê Triều Ngự Chế Âm Thi, 1954 (Reel 28)
  - Mục Lục in Nôm (Han) (Reel 29)
  - #1 (A44 #89) Công Dư Tiệp Ký (Han) (Reel 30)
  - #1 (A44 #89) Công Dư Tiệp Ký (Reel 31)
    Possibly a duplicate of the microfilm in box 30.
  - #3 (458) Tiên Thánh Văn Tập M. Durand (Reel 32)
  - #4 (A497 #318) Hà Thành Linh Tịch Cổ Lục (Reel 33)
  - #5 (#399) Song Phương Kỳ Duyên; Chiêu Quân Cống Hồ (Reel 34)
  - #6-2 (#218) Vân Trung Nguyệt Kính Tân Tuyện (Reel 35)
  - #6-3 (#352) Vân Cát Thân Nữ Cô Lục Diễn Âm (Reel 36)
  - #6-4 (#406) Lê Triều Nguyễn Tướng Công Huấn Ca (Reel 37)
  - #6.2 (AB19) Tam Thiên Tự Giải Âm (Reel 38)
  - #6.2 (AB42) Thế Tục Phú Thố Âm (Reel 39)
  - #8-1 Phạm Công Cúc Hoa (Reel 40)
  - #8-2 Thạch Sanh Lý Thông (Reel 41)
  - #8-3 Trần đại Lang Thơ (Reel 42)
  - #8-3 Trần đại Lang Thơ (Reel 43)
    Possibly a duplicate of the microfilm in box 42.
  - #8-4 Nữ Trung Báo Hoàn Thơ (Reel 44)
  - #8-5 (#174) Quốc Âm Diễn Thi (Han) (Reel 45)
  - #8-5 Chàng Nhài Kiên Thơ (Reel 46)
  - #9 (85) possibly also #77(39) Việt điện ũ linh hợp lục thất chi nhi (Reel 47)
  - #12 (AB281) Hảo Cần Tân Truyện (Reel 48)
  - #13 (AB953-188) Kim Vân Kiền Thanh Tâm (Reel 49)
  - #14 (A1829) Việt điện ũ linh tập (Reel 50)
  - #14 (A1829) Việt điện ũ linh tập (Reel 51)
    Possibly a duplicate of the microfilm in box 50.
  - #16 (#999) Ngũ Bách La Hán Tượng (Reel 52)
  - #16 (#999) Ngũ Bách La Hán Tượng (Reel 53)
    Possibly a duplicate of the microfilm in box 52.
  - #17 (AB2107) Lỉnh Nam Trích Quái Ngoại Chuyện (Han) (Reel 54)
  - #20 (A35-611) Đại Nam Chính Biên Liệt Truyện (Reel 55)
  - #22-1 (AB 298) Tiên Phả Dịch Lục (Hán) (Reel 56)
  - #31-1 (122 - #124) Thạch Sanh Truyện (Reel 57)
  - #31- 2 (122- #125) Tứ Linh Truyện (Reel 58)
  - #32-1(#589) An Lãng Chiêu Thuyền Tự Từ Đạo Hạnh Sự tích Thực Lục (Reel 59)
  - #31-3 (122- #126) Hoảng Trừu Tân Truyên (Reel 60)
  - #35-5 (AB 18) Huấn Nữ Diễm Ca (Reel 61)
  - #31-6 (57- #129) Tây Hồ Công Chúa Ngoại Sử (Reel 62)
  - #26-1 (AB 217) Tống Trân Tân Truyện (Reel 63)
  - #38-2 (17) Lê triều Dã Sứ (Reel 64)
  - #38-4 (320) Việt nam Phong Sử (Reel 65)
  - #60(6)-2 Phan Trần (Reel 66)
  - #36-5 (550- #458)Phật Tượng Đồ Vâng (Reel 67)
  - #170 (44- 47) Nam Quốc Phương Ngôn Tục Ngữ Bị Lực (Reel 68)
  - #121 Quốc Triều Chánh Biên Toát Yếu (Reel 69)
  - #143 U Tình Lục (Reel 70)
  - #144 Triết Nhơn Qúy Chính ĐôThơ I, II (Reel 71)
  - #148 Hoa Tiên De Nguyễn Huy Tủ (Reel 72)
  - #88 Triều Khôn Nhất Lãm (Reel 73)
  - #157 Con Tâm Con Cám Thư (Reel 74)
  - 159 -2 An Introduction to the Study of the Hakkas../ Dr Hsang Lin Lo, 1933 (Reel 75)
  - #171 Truyện Phương Hoa Mới (Reel 76)
  - #174 Quốc Âm Diển Thi M. Durand (Reel 77)
  - #177 (45) Chanson Vietnamiennes (Reel 78)
  - #178 Sứ Trình Đồ Bản (Reel 79)
  - (180) not on 1-38 list Comptw Rendud'une Amnassade Envoyee en Chine En 1825 (Reel 80)
  - #274-A607 (not on 1-38 list) Nghệ An Ký /Mai 1955 (Reel 81)
  - #314- #123 (not on 1-38 list) Việt nam tập Yếu-Cơte Historique (Reel 82)
  - #314 - #123 (not on 1-38 list) Costumes des Mandarins Civils (Reel 83)
  - AB269- #404(not on 1-38 list) Hoa Tiên /Mar 1955 (Reel 84)
  - AB32 #312 Kiến Văn Tiểu Lục (Reel 85)
  - A – 1919 Việt Điễn U Linh Tập (Hán) (Reel 86)
  - B-116 Trạch Sanh Lý Thông Thư (Hán) (Reel 87)
  - #60(6) not on1-38 list Lính Nam Trích Quái (Reel 88)
  - #62-8 (AB474) Series of short film pieces; Open with caution (Reel 89)
  - #27-3 (AB632) Mai Đình Mộng Ký (Reel 90)
  - #27-1 (AB469) Sô Nghiên Đối Hoại (Reel 91)
  - #27-4 Lưu Bình Dương Lễ Tân Truyện (Reel 92)
  - A.2674 Janvier 1953 Khâm Định Việt Sử Thông Giám vol. I, II, III (Reel 93)
  - A.2674 Janvier 1953 Khâm Định Việt Sử Thông Giám vol IV,V VI (Reel 94)
  - A.2674 Janvier 1953 Khâm Định Việt Sử Thông Giám vol VII, VIII, IX (Reel 95)
  - #22 à 33 Recueil des Lois et des Reglements de l' empire d' Annam Novemb.55, 1955 (Reel 96)
  - #1 à 20 Recueil des Loia et des Reglements de l'empire d' Annam Novemb.55, 1955 (Reel 97)
  - Fichier fonds Vietnamien par ordre alphabetique en caracteres chinois (Reel 98)
  - Catalogue du fonds chinois (biloliotheque du sud Vietnam ) au 31/3/54, 1954 (Reel 99)
  - Dictionaire Vietnamien Francais – de A a M 13- Juillet -1953 (Reel 100)
  - #159 Kuo Yu Chiek Ching methode de langue chinois parlee par les P.P. Franciseains 20/10/53, 1953 (Reel 101)
  - Phụ Nữ Tân Văn Mai 21, 1931 (Reel 102)
  - Nam Phong manquants 1922 à 1931 (Reel 103)
  - Nam Phong manquant 1932 (Reel 104)
  - #54 Đại Việt Sử Ký Tòan Thư vol: III et IV (Hán) (Reel 105)
  - A33(#186) Đại Nam Quốc Tiều Thế Hệ ̣(Hán) 8/2/54, 1954 (Reel 106)
  - A28 (#187) Quốc Triều Sử Toát Yêu (Hán) 10/2/54, 1954 (Reel 106)
  - Laboratoire de Hanoi 2,786 fiches A à Y (Reel 107)
  - Laboratoire de Hanoi 2,786 fiches A à Y (Reel 108)
  - Index Latini Sermonis (Reel 109)
  - #613(6737) Morceaux choises d'auteurs Vietnamien par G. Cordier., 1955 (Reel 110)
  - #614(Q 215) Nam Thi Hợp Tuyển par ôn như Nguyễn Văn Ngọc, 1955 (Reel 110)
  - #615(Q 377) Quang Trung Nguyễn Huệ̣ (1788-1792) par Hoa Bằng 14 Octobe 1955 (Reel 110)
  - A 1297 (#90) Vũ Trung Tùy Bút, 1952 (Reel 111)
  - A 3202 Việt điện u linh hợp lục thất chi nhi (Reel 112)
  - 8-208 Hoa tiên en quốc ngữ (Reel 112)
  - Đệ bạt tài tử (Reel 112)
  - #182 – 10000 caracteres chinois pourservir de modiles d'ecrilures (14/2/1954) (Reel 113)
  - #183 – cachetsdes mandarines et fonctiomavus sous la dynastes des Nguyễn (15/1/1954) (Reel 113)
  - #184- Đại Việt Sử ước (1-2-1954) (Reel 113)
  - #185 – Lic̣h Tiều Cỏ Chỉ (collection de Nguyễn Văn Cố) 2/2/1954 (Reel 113)
  - AB296(#604); AB643(#605) – Quốc âm thi ca tạp lục (Reel 114)
  - A2703(#606); A17(#607)– Lệ Triều Dã Sử (Reel 114)
  - A604(#608)- Quan văn tập (3 vols.) (Reel 114)
  - AB320(#609)- Việt nam Phong Sử (Reel 114)
  - A27(#610)- Đại nam thực lục liền biên (Reel 114)
  - A35(#611)- Đại nam chính biên liệt chuyện (Reel 114)
  - A2700(#612)- Khâm định Việt sử thông giám (Reel 114)
  - #151- Gương phong tục (Reel 115)
  - #152 – Chuyện hoa tiên (Reel 115)
  - #153 – Đại nam nhất thống chí (Reel 115)
  - #154 – Đại nam liệt truyện tiền biên (Reel 115)
  - #155 – Việt nam khaí quốc chí truyện (Reel 115)
  - Văn đại loài ngữ (Reel 116)
  - Nhật sung thương đàm (Reel 116)
  - Sự vật... (Reel 116)
  - Thiên nam toàn quốc (Reel 116)
  - Hương sơn quan thế âm (Reel 116)
  - Tháp nhi tiên nàng (Reel 116)
  - Nhị thập tư trung (Reel 116)
  - A1767(#447) – Lê mât tiết nghỉa lục (Reel 117)
  - A603(#448)- Du am ngâm tập (Reel 117)
  - A2704(#449)- Toàn le tiết nghỉa lục (Reel 117)
  - A608($450)- Hoàng việt thi tuyển (Reel 117)
  - A2691(#451)- Phan gia thế tự lục (Reel 117)
  - A23(#452)- Hoàng việt long hưng (Reel 117)
  - A2787(#453)- Tây sơn thủy mạt (Reel 118)
  - A117(#454)- Ngô gia văn phái (Reel 118)
  - A380(#455)- Tây sơn liệt truyện chính biên (Reel 118)
  - A2304(#456)-Tây sơn bang giao tập (Reel 118)
  - A17(#457)-Lê triều dả sử (Reel 118)
  - A550(#458)-Phật tương đố vàng (Reel 118)
  - A2981(#459)- Le mật tuẫn tiết chử thấn tính danh sự trạng (Reel 118)
  - A428(#462)-Tây sơn thuật lược (Reel 118)
  - In Hán Script (Reel 119)
  - In Hán Script (Reel 120)
  - Inventories of books and microfilms received with the collection (Box 121, Folder 1-2)